# Phil Tsarik

I am highly motivated person with 7 years experience in a front-end and back-end development. I have solid knowledge and experience in modern web technologies including JavaScript, NodeJs, AngularJs, Angular 2+, React, Redux. I have broad experience in conforming JavaScript and HTML/CSS code to work in old browsers. Experienced of working with legacy code. Familiar with mobile first approach, making responsive design. Experienced in developing of full stack web-applications using Ruby and Java.

I am experienced in designing solutions from scratch and establishing development processes on the project, including CI process. I have strong knowledge of design patterns and web platform specifics.

I have a very good feedback from customers, team members and managers. Enthusiastic about challenging tasks, fast learner, good team player with strong motivation and good communication skills. Always ready to participate in mentoring programs as a mentee and a mentor.

#### **Contacts:**

• Tel: +48 534 898 187

• Email: phil.tsarik@gmail.com

• Skype: phil.tsarik

• My legal name: Pilip Tsaryk

### Skill Overview

- Front end: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (incl. ES6+), TypeScript, Sass, Less, Angular (v1.x and v2+), React (and related technologies like Redux, MobX, Reflux, Preact, etc)
- Back end: Ruby, Python, Bash, Java, NodeJS, MySQL, PostgreSQL

# Experience

• JavaScript Developer, Dec 2017–Present (2 months)

Developing an application which is being used by 1M+ users every day.

I am responsible for UI development. All code is covered with BDD tests, unit-tests, integration tests.

Development process consists of Kanban methodology, merge requests for every story/task, code reviews of merge requests, CI to run tests and make builds.

- Company: EPAM Systems, Kraków Area, Poland

- Tools & technologies used: JavaScript, React, Reflux, SASS, Mustache templates, Webpack, Grunt, Karma, Jasmine, Git, Jira, Jenkins

### • JavaScript Developer, Nov 2015–Nov 2017 (25 months)

Developing a web-application for managing some specific hierarchy data which allows adding, removing, sorting, merging, exporting to Excel files, etc.

I am responsible for UI development. JavaScript code with business logic is covered by unit tests. I also perform code reviews of my collegues.

I take part in daily standups and weekly demos with the customer. I had a chance to show features invented by me from scratch to the customer.

- Company: EPAM Systems, Kraków Area, Poland
- Tools & technologies used: JavaScript, ES6, AngularJS 1.6, Redux, Bootstrap, Lodash, Webpack, Gulp, Bower, Karma, Jasmine, Protractor, Git, Jira, TeamCity

### • Front-End Developer, Jul 2016–Jun 2017 (12 months)

Taking part in a friend's startup as a front-end developer. This is a social network-like application for people in a specific area of business and it works together with some hardware devices.

Responsible for a whole front-end part.

Tools & technologies used: Angular 2, Material design, TypeScript, Lodash, NodeJS,
Webpack, Karma, Jasmine, Protractor, Git, Bitbucket, Jenkins, AWS

### • JavaScript Developer, Apr 2014–Oct 2015 (19 months)

Developing a client application for monitoring remote servers including separate versions for desktop and mobile browsers.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, UI development, manual testing, taking part in meetings, UI design, making mockups, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: JavaScript, Sencha Ext JS, Sencha Touch, SASS, SCCI protocol, Sencha Architect

#### • Full Stack Developer, Oct 2012–Feb 2014 (17 months)

Developing a firmware with Web GUI for network-attached storages based on Debian GNU/Linux. Developed and released a complete product with periodical updates with fixes and improvements.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, UI and back-end development, writing automated tests, manual testing, taking part in meetings, architecture and UI design, making mockups, collaborating with translators, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Debian, Ruby, Sinatra, Rspec, Haml, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Dropbox SDK, Jasmine, Git, Jenkins, Transifex, Jira

• Java Developer, Nov 2011–Sep 2012 (11 months)

Developing client-server application which provides remote management and configuration of servers.

- Company: SaM Solutions Gmbh, Minsk, Belarus
- Responsibilities: Planning, developing, testing, reporting
- Tools & technologies used: Java SE, Java RMI, Swing, JAXB, Windows PowerShell, SVN
- Full Stack Developer, Feb 2011–Aug 2012 (19 months)

Taking part in developing of a language learning service Langaroo.

- Responsibilities: UI and back-end development, writing automated tests, manual testing
- Tools & technologies used: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, ERB, SASS, Compass, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Git

# Education

• Polotsk State University, 2006–2011 Diploma in Software Engineering.

### **Appendix**

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/tsarik
- https://github.com/phts
- https://stackoverflow.com/users/2462524/phts

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the Personal Data Protection Act as of 29 August 1997, consolidated text: Journal of Laws 2016, item 922 as amended.

3